<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alex Kopf</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alex Kopf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why It&#39;s Called March Madness</title>
      <link>/2022/03/29/why-it-s-called-march-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/03/29/why-it-s-called-march-madness/</guid>
      <description>My notebook and game recipe was formed off of the classic sports saying, “offense is the best defense”. I believe that the fundamental thought that constantly scoring will result in a win, will apply to March Madness. The predictors I will use are effective fg %, true shooting %, rebounds, only offensive ,three point %, free throw %, point per game true shooting % and points per possession. I added free throw % and points per possession to the recipe because I think it matters if teams can capitalize off stopping their opponent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Ovechkin the Greatest Pure Goal Scorer of All Time?</title>
      <link>/2021/04/20/is-ovechkin-the-0greatest-pure-goal-scorer-of-all-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/20/is-ovechkin-the-0greatest-pure-goal-scorer-of-all-time/</guid>
      <description>As a hockey fan my entire life, and sharing the same first name, I have always been a fan of Russian superstar Alexander Ovechkin of the Washington Capitals. As he continues his career, Ovechkin is nearing Gretzky’s goal record more and more. Even if he doesn’t pass it, could he be considered right now as the best pure goal scorer of all time? Lets look at some data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do NHL Goalies Perform Better in the Postseason?</title>
      <link>/2021/03/30/do-nhl-goalies-perform-better-in-the-postseason/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/30/do-nhl-goalies-perform-better-in-the-postseason/</guid>
      <description>If you watch any team oriented sport, you will hear the phrase “Defense wins championships,”. However, I believe that in the NHL your goalie’s performance is even more enhanced compared to the regular season. If you watch the NHL playoffs most will agree there isn’t many other postseasons like it. The energy is unmatched. My belief is that if your goalie becomes “hot” in the playoffs they will win more games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning data</title>
      <link>/2021/03/29/cleaning-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/29/cleaning-data/</guid>
      <description>I am going to determine which games this college football season had the worst score differential
library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ─────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.3.0 ── ## ✓ ggplot2 3.3.3 ✓ purrr 0.3.4 ## ✓ tibble 3.0.3 ✓ dplyr 1.0.2 ## ✓ tidyr 1.1.2 ✓ stringr 1.4.0 ## ✓ readr 1.4.0 ✓ forcats 0.5.0 ## ── Conflicts ────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse_conflicts() ── ## x dplyr::filter() masks stats::filter() ## x dplyr::lag() masks stats::lag() badlogs &amp;lt;- read.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
